We’re eating more fish than ever these days.
如今，我们吃的鱼比以往任何时候都多。
At around 20 kilograms per person, global fish consumption is now more than twice what it was in the 1960s.
全球鱼类消费量现已达到人均约20千克，是20世纪60年代的两倍多。
What’s really remarkable, though, is where that fish comes from.
不过，真正引人注目的是这些鱼从哪里来。
For the first time in human history, most of our aquatic food now comes from farming rather than fishing.
如今，我们的水产食品大部分来自养殖，而非捕捞，这在人类历史上尚属首次。
People ate around 73 million tonnes of farmed fish—just more than half of the volume of fish that humans consumed—in 2014.
2014年，人们吃掉了约7300万吨养殖鱼，略多于人类当年鱼类消费总量的一半。
That’s out of a total fish supply of 167 million tonnes; the remaining 20 million or so tonnes go into things like animal feed and medical products.
鱼类总供应量为1.67亿吨，人类消费的鱼就出自其中；其余2000万吨左右则用来制作动物饲料、医疗产品等。
To keep eating fish at the current rate, we’re definitely going to need to keep aquaculture developing.
要按目前的速度继续吃鱼，我们肯定需要让水产养殖持续发展。
That’s because the volume of fish caught in the wild has leveled off since the 1990s.
这是因为自20世纪90年代以来，野外捕捞的鱼量就已趋于平稳。
Back in 1974, only 10% of marine fish stocks had been overfished.
1974年时，只有10%的海洋鱼类种群遭到了过度捕捞。
Now, more than three-tenths are.
如今，这一比例已超过十分之三。
Only a tenth of our oceans’ fish stocks could sustain heavier fishing than current levels.
我们海洋里的鱼类种群中，只有十分之一能承受高于目前水平的捕捞强度。
But while catches at sea have suffered, fish-farming has been growing at a fast rate.
但是，尽管海上捕捞量受到了冲击，鱼类养殖却一直在快速增长。
A lot of that is coming from China, which produces 60% of the world’s farmed fish.
这一增长很大一部分来自中国，中国的养殖鱼产量占全世界的60%。
In fact, some 35 countries, including China, now produce more farmed than wild-caught fish.
事实上，如今包括中国在内约有35个国家，养殖鱼产量高于野生捕捞鱼产量。
This shift toward aquaculture isn’t just good for ensuring salmon on your plate; it’s also crucial to ensuring food security and sustainability.
这种向水产养殖的转变不仅有利于确保你的餐盘里有三文鱼，对保障粮食安全和可持续性也至关重要。
By 2050, the world will need to feed an estimated 9.7 billion people.
到2050年，世界需要养活的人口估计将达到97亿。
They’ll have to get their protein somewhere.
他们总得从某个地方获取蛋白质。
However, raising cattle, pigs, and other land-based animals requires vast amounts of grain and water.
然而，饲养牛、猪等陆生动物需要大量的谷物和水。
For example, pound for pound, beef requires 15 times more feed to raise than carp, a freshwater fish farmed all over Asia.
例如，养出同等重量的牛肉和鲤鱼，前者所需的饲料是后者的15倍；鲤鱼是一种在亚洲各地都有养殖的淡水鱼。
That grain—and the water needed to grow it—could be consumed by people instead.
这些谷物，连同种植谷物所需的水，本可以转而供人类消费。
However, aquaculture is no silver bullet.
然而，水产养殖并非万全之策。
In some Southeast Asian countries, shrimp farming does disastrous damage to marine ecosystems.
在一些东南亚国家，养虾业对海洋生态系统造成灾难性的破坏。
Despite these problems, however, shrimp continues to be among the most popular seafoods worldwide.
然而，尽管存在这些问题，虾仍然是全世界最受欢迎的海鲜之一。